地         球         脉         动   I I
地球是人类已知的唯一存在生命的星球
Earth is the only planet we know of where life exists.
而且这里生机盎然
And, here, it does so in abundance.
丛林宛如伊甸园般美好
The jungle is Eden.
它仅占地球表面积的百分之六
It covers less than 6% of the Earth's surface
却分布着世界上
but it's home to half of all
一半的动植物物种
the plants and animals on land.
丛林拥有适宜的光照  水源和养分
Jungles have just the right amount of light, water and nutrients,
千百年来一直如此
and they have had every day for millennia.
在这里生存应该不难
Life here should be easy.
这是一只大狐猴
This is an indri.
他和我们一样  是灵长类动物
It's a primate, like us.
马达加斯加的这片森林就是他的家
And these forests in Madagascar are its home.
但是要在这里生存
But to survive here...
他不得不面对一个巨大的挑战
it has to face one major challenge.
天堂有点拥挤
Paradise is crowded.
每个角落都有物种栖息
Life fills every niche.
每分每秒
And, at any one time,
都有生命为了空间与食物斗争不已
a staggering variety of species and countless individuals
种类繁多  数不胜数
are striving for space and food.
和所有丛林中的动物一样
Like every jungle animal,
大狐猴需要找到自己的方法
indri have to find their own way to survive
才能在地球上竞争最为激烈的地方生存下去
in the most competitive place on Earth.
丛          林
画 外 音
大卫 · 爱登堡   爵士
丛林错综复杂
Jungles are complex places...
丰富的热带植物
tangled three-dimensional worlds
交织出一个立体世界
created by lush tropical vegetation.
这里有九成的动物在树上度过一生
90% of the animals here spend their whole lives up in the trees.
每一种动物都有自己的生存之道
And each of them has to find its own way of getting around.
一只蜘蛛猴悬挂于距离地面三十米高的地方
Hanging 100 feet above the ground, a spider monkey.
他们以家庭为单位行动
They travel in family groups
在丛林的最上层获取生存的必需品
and find everything they need in the top storey of the jungle.
这么高的地方可不适合胆小的物种
Up here isn't a place for the faint-hearted.
修长的四肢加上灵活如手的卷尾
With long limbs and a prehensile tail that can grip like a hand,
他们就是为攀爬而生的
they're built for climbing.
但是要在这么高的地方学习这些技巧
But imagine having to learn these skills as high up as this.
三分之一的蜘蛛猴都活不到成年
One third of spider monkeys never make it to adulthood.
这只幼崽只有几个月大
This youngster is only a few months old.
她的未来取决于她的攀爬能力
Her future depends on her ability to climb.
通过和哥哥姐姐在练习树上玩耍
Playing on a practice tree with her older brother and sister,
她已经学会用尾巴当安全索
she's already learning to use her tail as a safety line...
一切都在父亲的注视之下
under her father's close watch.
她很想加入游戏  但是由于年纪最小
She's keen to join in the game but she's the youngest and,
有时候不太受大家欢迎
as is the way of things, she's not always welcome.
所以她自己找了个地方玩耍
So she chooses her own place to play.
但是树木不尽相同
But not all trees are the same.
这棵树需要更高的攀爬技巧
This one is for more advanced climbers.
论积极性  毋庸置疑
Enthusiasm? Certainly!
但论技术
Technique?
有待提高
Room for improvement.
此时她的几个家庭成员
Meanwhile, some of her family have moved on
去其它地方寻找新鲜食物了
to look for a new patch of fresh food.
树冠顶端不是幼猴该去的地方
The top of the canopy isn't for youngsters.
可父亲没有看着她  加入大家的诱惑
But father's not looking and the temptation to join the others
又实在无法抗拒
is irresistible.
她必须小心翼翼
She'll need to be careful.
从这里跌落必死无疑
A fall from here would mean certain death.
这是她第一次独自爬到如此高的地方
It's the first time she's been as high as this on her own.
她越爬越高  树枝越来越细
As she climbs still higher, the branches get thinner and thinner.
尾巴救了她一命
Her tail has caught her...
可她现在被困在空中
...but now she's stuck in mid-air,
够不到其它的树枝
unable to reach any other branch.
而父亲其实一直关注着
Father, however, was watching.
他的身体强壮有力
He's big and strong enough
可以搭成一座桥
to form a bridge with his body
让孩子爬回安全地带
so that she can climb to safety.
吃一堑长一智
Lesson learned.
但是在树顶生活的不仅仅是猴子
But it's not just monkeys that live here, up in the treetops.
如果体型足够小
And, if you are small,
找一棵合适的树相当于找到了一生的家
finding the right tree can mean a home for life.
这是一只飞蜥
He's a Draco lizard.
体型只有铅笔大小  以蚂蚁为食
He's only the size of a pencil and he eats ants.
这棵树可以为他提供一生所需的食物
This one tree could provide him with all he will ever need...
就像回转寿司一样源源不断
a conveyor belt of food.
这是完美的栖身之所
It's a perfect place to settle down.
本来是的
Well, it would be...
可这里已经有蜥蜴安家了
...but there's already someone here.
这只大点的雄蜥蜴是这棵树的主人
This larger male is the tree's owner.
而飞蜥从不分享
And Dracos don't share.
主人的旗帜是个警告
The owner's flag is a warning.
对入侵者绝不手软
Trespassers won't be tolerated.
他不仅是在恐吓对手
The owner's not only intimidating...
同时也做好了战斗的准备
...he's prepared to battle.
无处可逃了
A dead end.
形势万分危急
Safety is a long way away.
现在他必须做出选择
Now he must choose.
迎战
Fight...
还是逃跑
...or flee?
只有在丛林中你才能看到
Only in the jungle do you find lizards
像龙一样翱翔的蜥蜴
that can soar like dragons.
他纵身一跃可以飞出三十余米
He can travel over 100 feet in a single leap.
这是一种高速而有效的穿越丛林的方式
It's a very fast and efficient way to move through the jungle.
没准这会是一棵无人占领而又食物充足的树
Maybe this new tree will have food and no resident owner.
丛林中的所有物种都在争夺生存空间
Everything in the jungle has to compete for space.
只有百分之二的光线会到达地面
Only 2% of the sun's rays reach the ground...
所以即使是植物也要争夺生长
...so even the plants must battle for the light they need
所需的阳光
if they're to grow.
三百年前这棵响盒子就开始努力汲取阳光
300 years ago, this Hura tree began its race for light.
日复一日地
And every day since,
它吸收着成长所需的水分和阳光
it has absorbed the water and sunshine it needed
终于长成参天大树
to grow into a giant.
它与其他树木一样努力生长
It has succeeded in doing what every tree must do to survive...
终于摆脱丛林底层的昏暗  脱颖而出
...rise above the gloom of the jungle floor.
不仅如此  它还养活了很多其它的生命
And, what is more, its success has given life to others.
它的树枝上长着千余种植物
Its branches now carry 1,000 other plants.
这些蕨类  无花果和兰科植物
These particular ferns, figs and orchids
只在寄生在其他树木的树枝上
live only on the branches of other trees.
近千种植物在一棵树上济济一堂
1,000 plants growing on one single tree.
整片森林之中  这样的情景随处可见
Throughout the forest, this story is repeated endless times.
正因如此  丛林中植物物种的数量
As a consequence, jungles are home
是地球上最多的
to more species of plants than anywhere else on Earth.
而这些植被成为大量动物赖以生存的家园
And they, in turn, support a wealth of animals.
在厄瓜多尔  生存竞争尤为激烈
In Ecuador, the competition is at its most intense.
在这里  光是蜂鸟就有一百种
Here, there are 100 species of hummingbirds alone...
都在争夺花蜜
...all fighting for nectar.
每朵花一次只能产出少量花蜜
Each flower only has a small amount at any one time,
所以先到先得
and so it's first come, first served.
这种蜂鸟竭尽全力
One hummingbird has gone to great lengths
试图避免与其他物种的争斗
to avoid conflict with other species.
刀嘴蜂鸟是唯一一种喙长于身体的鸟类
Swordbills are the only bird with a beak longer than their body.
有些植物花冠极其细长
And some flowers are too elongated
其它九十九种蜂鸟
for the other 99 species of hummingbirds here
都无法吃到里面的花蜜
to feed from them.
刀嘴蜂鸟凭借极长的喙
A swordbill's extraordinary beak, however,
可以够到其它蜂鸟无法触及的地方
enables it to reach the places that others can't...
也就是这种花朵基部的蜜腺
...the top of this flower, where the sweet nectar is produced.
它找到了解决方法
It has found a solution
不必和其它蜂鸟争夺食物
that means it doesn't have to join the fight.
细长的花朵们竞相盛开
And, as each long flower blooms,
为刀嘴蜂鸟提供了专属的新鲜花蜜
it gives the swordbill a fresh supply of food all to itself.
不过  喙比身体长也是有缺点的
But having a beak longer than your body does have its drawbacks.
首先  想保持干净就有点难度
For a start, it's tricky to keep it clean.
更麻烦的是  要如何整理羽毛呢
Harder still, how do you preen your body feathers?
不像其它蜂鸟
Unlike the other hummers,
刀嘴蜂鸟的喙够不到身上的羽毛
swordbills can't reach their feathers with their beak.
唯一的办法就是用爪子挠
The only option, a good old scratch.
虽然不太优雅
It's a little unrefined...
但这是独享食物要付出的一点小代价
...but a small price to pay for an exclusive food supply...
尤其是进食时间
...especially when feeding times
经常被暴雨天气打断的时候
are only too frequently interrupted by storms.
丛林是地球上自然资源最丰富的地区
Jungles are the richest places on Earth
个中原因令人惊奇
because of one remarkable fact...
丛林能够自己制造天气
...they make their own weather.
每天水分都会从叶表蒸发  变成水蒸气
Every day, water rises from the surface of the leaves as vapour.
如同树木在呼出云
It's as if the trees breathe out clouds.
水汽逐渐集结在森林上空  直到...
They gather over the forest until, finally...
汇成倾盆大雨
...they burst.
雨是丛林的命脉
Rain is the lifeblood of every jungle.
动物们每天都要经受暴雨的考验
And all have to do their best to endure the daily downpour.
有一些丛林  比如巴西的这里
In some jungles, like here in Brazil,
由于降雨量特别大  一年中总有一段时间
it rains so much that, for part of the year,
树木几乎被完全淹没
the trees are almost totally submerged.
水面至林地表层深达九米
The forest floor is 30 feet below the water's surface.
这是一个神秘的世界
This is a mysterious world,
鲜少有人踏足
a place few people have ever explored.
这里分布的许多动物
We have much to discover
都值得我们去探索
about the animals for which this is home...
有些物种你可能从未想过会在丛林里见到
...including some you might never expect to find amongst trees.
距离海洋一千六百公里的这个地方  有江豚
Here, 1,000 miles from the sea, are dolphins.
这种淡水豚是一个新种
A newly identified species of river dolphin
在地球上其它地方均无分布
found nowhere else on Earth.
由于生活在黑暗而复杂的河水里
In these black, tangled waters,
他们的双眼几乎完全失明
they have become almost totally blind,
所以他们游得很慢
so they move slowly,
仔细地用声纳扫描林地表层寻找鱼类为食
carefully using their sonar to scan the forest floor for fish.
如果这片森林里能隐居着新种江豚
If this forest can hide a new species of dolphin...
那还会有多少新奇物种  等着我们去发现呢
...what else might there be here, awaiting discovery?
这片泛洪丛林边缘的泥岸浅水区
At the shallow margins of the flooded jungle,
河流穿过茂密的植被
rivers flow through lush vegetation.
这里食物充足  养育着一些大型动物
Here, food is so abundant, it supports giants.
水豚  世界上最大的啮齿动物
Capybara, the biggest rodents in the world...
大水獭  体型堪比成年男性
...giant otters the size of a man...
还有称霸河流的王者
...and the rulers of these rivers...
凯门鳄
...caiman.
它们体长可达三米
They grow to ten feet long and kill anything
能杀死一切落入口中的猎物
they get between their jaws.
然而还有更狡猾的捕猎者
But there are more artful hunters...
从周围的森林里被吸引至此
...drawn here from the surrounding forest.
美洲豹  丛林中顶端的捕食者
A jaguar, the supreme jungle predator.
这条河是他领地的边界
The river marks the edge of his territory...
但在这里  他遇到了竞争对手
...but here he has competition.
他闯入了一只母美洲豹的地盘
He's now in the territory of a female.
她统治这一河段已有五年之久
She has ruled this stretch of river for five years.
这是她狩猎的地方
This is her place to hunt.
水豚既强壮又机警
Capybara are strong and wary.
狩猎关键在于悄无声息
The key is stealth.
想袭击它们  她必须靠近到一米之内
She needs to get within three feet if she's to pounce.
这次没成功
Not this time.
她不是这里唯一的母豹
She's not the only female here.
在丛林边缘的不同区域  各有一只母豹称后
Each part of this jungle's edge is ruled by a different queen.
很少地方有足够的食物能养活这么多只大猫
Few places on Earth have enough food to support so many big cats.
公美洲豹的捕猎方式则有所不同
The male hunts in a different way.
一百三十公斤的体重  很难做到悄无声息
Weighing almost 300 lbs, it's hard to be stealthy...
加上周围还有很多美洲豹
...and with so many other jaguars around,
他就不费心去抓警觉的水豚了
he doesn't bother with wary capybara.
他寻找另一种猎物
He seeks a different prey.
他成了捕猎杀手的杀手
He's become a killer of killers.
美洲豹的咬合力是所有猫科动物里最强的
Jaguars have the most powerful bite of any cat.
而且他知道凯门鳄最脆弱的部位
And he knows the caiman's most vulnerable point...
是它的后脑勺
...the back of its skull.
在浓密的丛林底层中生活的捕猎者
Hunters living in the dense understorey of the jungle
形态各异
come in all shapes and sizes.
但它们有一个共同的难题
But they share a problem.
如何分辨植物和猎物
How to tell what is a plant, and what is prey.
这是个捉迷藏游戏
This is a game of hide and seek
眨眼间就能定输赢
that can be won or lost in the blink of an eye.
捕猎者和猎物之间经过漫长的斗争
The long contest between predator and prey
形成了令人震惊的拟态水平
has produced mimicry of astounding accuracy.
一只叶尾壁虎正伪装成地衣
A leaf-tailed gecko masquerading as lichen.
有些动物把伪装发挥到更高境界
Some animals take camouflage a stage further still...
在哥斯达黎加的这条小溪里
...and these streams in Costa Rica
住着一位杰出的伪装大师
are home to one of the most remarkable.
一只玻璃蛙
A glass frog.
这只雄蛙尺寸迷你  只有人的指甲大小
A male, and tiny, no bigger than your fingernail
身体几乎完全透明
and almost entirely transparent...
这很有必要
...as he needs to be.
几乎所有经过这里的动物  都能吃掉它
Almost everything that walks past here could eat him,
甚至是一只蟋蟀
even a cricket.
想活命  它就要保持静止不动
His best chance is to stay absolutely still
希望蟋蟀的视线能直接穿透它
and trust that the cricket looks right through him.
危险过去了
Danger passed,
幸好如此
and that's just as well,
因为他作为一名父亲
because he is a father...
正在保护珍贵的卵
...and he's guarding some very precious eggs.
过去几周  雌蛙们相继来和他交配
For the last few weeks, females, one after the other,
并将保护后代的重任交给他
have visited him and entrusted him with their offspring.
有些卵快孵化了
Some are now almost ready to hatch.
叶子上有几团卵块  最上面的那一团
There are several clutches on the leaf, and those at the top,
是最近产下的  还不到一天大
the most recently laid, are barely a day old.
可是在丛林里  总有其它动物虎视眈眈
But in the jungle, there's always someone out to get you.
这只黄蜂是捕食蛙卵的专家
This wasp is a specialist hunter of frogs' eggs.
它在叶子底部发现了正在蠕动的小蝌蚪们
It's noticed the wriggling tadpoles at the bottom of the leaf.
他决不能移动
He mustn't move.
刚产下的卵是最脆弱的
The youngest eggs are the most vulnerable,
他无法同时保护所有的卵
and he can't guard them all.
但这些小蝌蚪并不像表面看起来那样无助
But these tadpoles are not as helpless as they might appear.
难以置信的是  未孵化的蝌蚪能感应到危险
Incredibly, the unhatched tadpoles can sense danger,
那些最成熟和最强壮的
and the oldest and strongest
可以扭动着挣脱出来  掉进下方的溪流里
wriggle free and drop into the stream below.
然而叶子顶部的卵
The eggs at the top of the leaf, however,
还未能孵化
are still too young to hatch,
但黄蜂已经知道它们的存在
and now the wasps know they're there.
不过雄蛙的背部
But the male's back
看起来很像新产下的卵块
looks very like the youngest cluster of eggs...
这似乎迷惑住了黄蜂
...and that seems to confuse the wasps.
拿自己的身体当诱饵非常冒险
Using his own body as a decoy is a huge risk.
如果被黄蜂蛰伤  他会送命的
The wasp stings could kill him.
他成功救下了大部分的后代
He's managed to save most of his young.
他还得再保持警惕两周
He'll have to remain on guard for another two weeks,
不过在丛林里
but in the jungle,
能活过一天都算是一种胜利
just surviving the day can count as a success.
当夜幕降临
With the coming of the night,
另一批丛林主角们登上了舞台
a new cast of jungle characters takes to the stage.
飞虫们开始为寻找伴侣而发光
Flying insects begin to glow as they search for mates.
菌类与植物不同
Fungi, unlike plants,
在阴暗的森林地面茁壮地成长
thrive in the darkness of the forest floor.
它们隐匿起来  直到绽放的时刻
They're hidden until they begin to develop
便以惊人的姿态生长繁殖
the incredible structures with which they reproduce.
每株蘑菇释放出数以百万的微型孢子
Each releases millions of microscopic spores
无形地飘散各处
that drift invisibly away.
许多长出子实体的蘑菇
Many have fruiting bodies
努力朝上生长  以捕捉潮湿空气中
that reach upwards to catch any feeble current
可能存在的稀薄氧气
there might be in the clammy air.
然而这一株  长着长着
But this one, as it grows,
却发起了光
becomes luminous.
蘑菇发光的原因一直是个谜团
Why fungi light up has remained a mystery...
直到现在才被解开
...until now.
科学家研究了世界上最亮的蘑菇
Scientists studying the brightest fungi in the world
认为他们或许找到了答案
think they may have an answer.
光线像灯塔一样吸引着昆虫
Like a beacon, the light attracts insects.
从四处赶来
From far and wide.
对这只扣头虫来说  光亮只意味着一件事...
To this click beetle, a bright light means only one thing...millennia
一只雌性扣头虫
a female click beetle,
所以他亦发光回应
so he flashes in reply.
但没有得到预期的反应
But he doesn't get the reception he was expecting.
他疑惑不解  开始四处寻找雌虫
Confused, he starts searching for a female,
这可帮了蘑菇的大忙
and that helps the fungus.
当他放弃的时候  浑身已沾满了蘑菇的孢子
By the time he gives up, he's covered in the fungus's spores.
在他继续寻找雌虫时
And, as he continues his quest for a female,
也一同将这些孢子传播到了森林他处
he carries these spores to other parts of the forest.
这晚  丛林中还有更奇特的东西在发光
And there are even stranger things glowing in the jungle night.
这是火车虫（苹绕实蝇）的多彩灯光
These are the multicoloured lights of a railroad worm.
然而它并不是一种蠕虫
It's not really a worm,
而是一种酷似毛毛虫的有毒甲虫
but a poisonous, caterpillar-like beetle.
黄灯亮起  以警告其他动物莫要挡道
The yellow lights warn other creatures to keep out of its way.
它在寻找千足虫
It's hunting for millipedes.
当它发现可疑踪迹时
When it finds the trail of one,
便会熄灭黄灯
it switches off its yellow lights.
现在它仅留一盏头顶的红灯
Now it only has a red light on its head.
千足虫看不见红光
Millipedes can't see red light.
所以对它们来说  火车虫已经
So, to them, the railroad worm
切换成了完全隐身的潜行模式
in stealth mode is virtually invisible.
千足虫的生命终结了
And that is the end of the millipede.
丛林中的生存竞争迫使动物们在方方面面
Competition in the jungles forces animals to specialise
都成了生活的行家
in every aspect of their life,
包括求偶
including courtship.
这也催生出了一些地球上
This has produced some of the most beautiful
最美秒最精巧的展示
and elaborate displays on the planet.
一只红色的雄性天堂鸟
A male red bird-of-paradise,
正在用舞蹈来争取一只雌鸟的青睐
competing to attract a female by dancing.
她来看看是否有佳偶在此等候
One has come to survey what's on offer.
她是一位独立有主见的女士
She is an independent lady,
可以任意选择自己中意的男士
and she will select whichever male takes her fancy.
她作出了选择
She makes her choice.
但这会儿好像又不太确定
But now she doesn't seem quite so sure.
不行吗
No?
可能他有点太急切了
Perhaps he's just a little too keen.
也许明天他会好运一些
Maybe he'll have better luck tomorrow.
红色天堂鸟在树梢间炫技求偶
Red birds-of-paradise display in the treetops.
而家族里的其他成员
Other members of the family
却在森林地面的阴暗处起舞
dance in the gloom of the forest floor.
这是一只威尔逊天堂鸟
This is a Wilson's bird-of-paradise.
他颜色艳丽  但只有麻雀大小
He's brightly coloured, but about the size of a sparrow.
他之前大多独自生活  但现在成年了
He's lived most of his life alone, but now he's an adult,
急需吸引一位伴侣
and he too needs to attract a mate.
这个小光斑或许能帮到他
This little patch of light might help him do so.
首先  他把这里收拾干净
First, he tidies things up.
在一堆杂乱的树叶间炫耀舞技可不容易
Showing off in this jumble of leaves wouldn't be easy,
简单的背景才更能衬托他的美丽
and his beauty will stand out better against a plain background.
他可不希望鲜艳的叶子转移了观众的注意
He doesn't want bright leaves to divert a visitor's attention.
它们都得被清理掉
They all need to go.
就连绿色的也不能留
Even the green ones.
尤其是绿色的
Especially the green ones.
他的舞台搭好了
His stage is set.
一个中心支柱  一点光斑
A central pole, and a little patch of light.
完美
It's perfect.
现在  他必须期待雌鸟能听见他的呼唤
And now, he must hope a female hears his call.
他能在这里连等上几周
He can wait here for weeks on end.
终于  雌鸟来了
At last, a female.
是时候就位了
Time to take up position.
雌鸟要通过雄鸟羽毛的光泽来衡量他
She will judge him by the brightness of his feathers.
但为了向雌鸟展示他的最佳状态
But for the female to see him at his best,
他需要她落座于舞台的正上方
he needs her to perch directly above his stage,
在那束阳光下
under the light.
这也许是他唯一一次闪耀的机会
This might be his only chance to shine.
现在  当她垂直俯视他的时候
Now, when she's looking directly down on him,
他只为她的目光而表演
he reveals a display for her eyes only.
在这森林地表的阴暗处
In the gloom of the forest floor,
他就是那最绚烂最夺目的一抹绿色
he is a dazzling blaze of iridescent green.
森林里最耀眼的叶子
The brightest leaf in the forest.
他成功了
And that does the trick.
每个动物都必须找到独家方法
Each animal must find its own way of
才能在丛林的竞争中生存下来
surviving the competition of the jungle.
这个拥挤的世界充满了创造力
This crowded world is so full of invention
几乎陆地上所有的物种
that almost all kinds of animals on land
都能从这里找到起源
can trace their origins back here...
包括人类
...including us.
马达加斯加的这片森林
These forests in Madagascar
是我们一位远亲的家园
are home to one of our distant cousins.
这只雌性大狐猴
This female indri
曾为她和家族能在森林里有一处安身之地
has fought to keep this particular patch of forest
而英勇奋战
safe for herself and her family.
每天清晨  家族成员们聚在一起歌唱
Every morning, the family come together to sing,
她们在提醒别人这是她们的家园
their way of reminding others that this is their home.
大狐猴非常适应这里的生存环境
Indri are so closely adapted to living here
以至于现在已无法生存于别处
that now they can live nowhere else.
对她们以及其他数十亿
For them and the billions of animals with whom
共享家园的动物来说
they share their home,
丛林是个庇护所
the jungle is a sanctuary.
然而一切正遭受着变故
But this is changing.
在家族首领出生的这十年里
Even in the ten years since the head of this family was born,
仅在马达加斯加  就有一百万公顷的雨林
one million hectares of the rainforest have been destroyed
遭到破坏
in Madagascar alone,
而那里曾栖息着半数的大狐猴家族
and, with it, half the indri families that once lived there.
当地居民说  大狐猴是我们的兄弟
The local people say the indris are our brothers
他们的歌声也是在提醒我们
and their song is a call to remind us that we, too,
人类也曾经依靠丛林为生
once depended on the jungle.
这片伊甸园仍是充满奇迹和魔法的天堂
This Eden is still a place of wonder and magic.
有些生命  毋庸置疑  值得我们保护
Something, surely, worth protecting.
下一集
Next time...
极端的生存环境把生命推向极限
A land of extremes that pushes life to the limit.
动物们自有非同寻常的方法
Animals have extraordinary ways
来应对险恶的生存环境
of dealing with the hostile conditions.
由此创造出了地球上最伟大的生存壮举
Creating the most epic survival stories on Earth.
这就是沙漠
These are deserts.